Andrew Bridger

(m) +44 7759 512091 andrewjohnbridger@gmail.com

Professional Overview

I am an Economist who is passionate about applying and communicating economic principles to create better outcomes for all. I have 5 years' professional experience in economic policy and research. I am on a sabbatical from the Australian Industry Group, where I hold a Senior Economist role, to complete my Masters in Economics at the University of Edinburgh, Scotland.

Professional Experience

Senior Economist (on sabbatical in the United Kingdom)
The Australian Industry Group (Ai Group)

Dec 2017 – Current Melbourne, Australia

Responsible for analysis and commentary on Australian and international economic developments.

Key responsibilities:

- Providing economic advice and research
- Presenting economic updates to Government agencies, journalists and business
- Preparing Ai Group business surveys and research reports
- Statistical analysis
- Policy analysis

Graduate Department of Industry, Innovation and Science

Feb 2016 – Dec 2017 Canberra, Australia

Employed as part of the two-year graduate program. Worked across the budget process, industry growth sectors and modelling workforce requirements to deliver government services.

Key responsibilities as a Data Analyst include:

- Modelling workforce requirements and making recommendations based on the modelling to the Executive
- Budget analysis
- Working on whole-of-division projects

Research Economist Synergies Economic Consulting

Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Brisbane, Australia

Hired as a summer intern and upon completion of my internship, I was asked to stay on while finishing my university studies.

Key responsibilities:

- Economic research on wheat supply chains, port facilities and the energy market
- Policy updates
- Report writing

Early Career Summary

Ipsos Research Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewer	2013 - 2015
Strut N Fret Festival Bar Team Bartender	2012 - 2014
Direct 2 Consumer (D2C) Brand Ambassador	2011 - 2012

Qualifications

Master of Science in Economics University of Edinburgh

2021 - Current Edinburgh, UK

• Course component will be done by May 2022

Bachelor of Commerce/Economics University of Queensland

2011-2015

Brisbane, Australia

- Majored in Finance (Commerce) and Quantitative Methods (Economics)
- Grade Point Average of 5.6 (out of 7)
- Exchange semesters at the University of Massachusetts and Kansas State University
- 2012 Dean's Commendation for High Achievement

Graduate Certificate in Management (Public Sector) University of Canberra

2017

Canberra, Australia

• Grade Point Average of 6.0 (out of 7)

Summary of Skills

- Data analysis to inform decision-making
- Excellent written communication skills
- Statistical software (R and EViews)
- Advanced excel skills
- Enthusiasm for responsibility
- Attention to detail

Referees

Julie Toth
The Australian Industry Group
Chief Economist
Contact details available on request

Lisa Hind

Department of Industry, Innovation and Science General Manager - State and Territory Network within AusIndustry Contact details available on request

Jeffrey Lassen

Managing Director at FTI Consulting Former Principal at Synergies Economic Consulting Contact details available on request